[
    {
        "question": "Who invented Java Programming?",
        "choice1": "Guido van Rossum",
        "choice2": "James Gosling",
        "choice3": "Dennis Ritchie",
        "choice4": "Bjarne Stroustrup",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
        "choice1": "JRE",
        "choice2": "JIT",
        "choice3": "JDK",
        "choice4": "JVM",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a Java feature?",
        "choice1": "Object-oriented",
        "choice2": "Use of pointers",
        "choice3": "Portable",
        "choice4": "Dynamic and Extensible",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java?",
        "choice1": "identifier & keyword",
        "choice2": "identifier",
        "choice3": "keywords",
        "choice4": "none of the mentioned",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the extension of java code files?",
        "choice1": ".js",
        "choice2": ".txt",
        "choice3": ".class",
        "choice4": ".java",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Which environment variable is used to set the java path?",
        "choice1": "MAVEN_Path",
        "choice2": "JavaPATH",
        "choice3": "JAVA",
        "choice4": "JAVA_HOME",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?",
        "choice1": "Polymorphism",
        "choice2": "Inheritance",
        "choice3": "Compilation",
        "choice4": "Encapsulation",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "What is not the use of “this” keyword in Java?",
        "choice1": "Referring to the instance variable when a local variable has the same name",
        "choice2": "Passing itself to the method of the same class",
        "choice3": "Passing itself to another method",
        "choice4": "Calling another constructor in constructor chaining",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a type of polymorphism in Java Programming",
        "choice1": "Multiple polymorphism",
        "choice2": "Compile time polymorphism",
        "choice3": "Multilevel polymorphism",
        "choice4": "Execution time polymorphism",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Truncation in Java?",
        "choice1": "Floating-point value assigned to a Floating type",
        "choice2": "Floating-point value assigned to an integer type",
        "choice3": "Integer value assigned to floating type",
        "choice4": "Integer value assigned to double type",
        "answer": 2
    }
]